

# **Chantal Vriens**

## interaction designer

Hello, my name is Chantal Vriens and I am a Master Student in Industrial Design at the Eindhoven University of Technology. I enjoy working on the development of new and innovative products and experiences using data and technology.

#### Skills & Interest

- Programming processing, html, javascript, arduino, c# (unity)
- Adobe Creative Suite illustrator, photoshop, indesign, lightroom.
- User Research

- Design Prototyping invision, arduino, 3D printing, solid works.
- Data collection and visualisation
- Other tools miro, microsoft office.

#### Contact me

Mail vrienschantal@gmail.com

Phone +31613757265

Adres Deken van Somerenstraat 33

5611KX Eindhoven

Social https://www.linkedin.com/

in/chantalyriens/

#### Education

### Eindhoven University of Technology MSc Industrial Design

Throughout the Master I am further developping my skillset as a user-experience designer focused on technology and (digital) interaction design. In my designs I want to explore the usages of data in a broad range of application fields. Focussing my design on the conceptualisation and evaluation of these emerging technologies through the development of prototypes.

#### University of Twente Pre-master Industrial Design

Broadening my toolkit and bridging the gap between my current knowledge and the knowledge needed for the Industrial Design Master through following courses from the Industrial Design Bachelor. This mainly concerns technical courses like technical drawing, production, solid works and statics.

## University of Twente BSc Creative Technology Average: 8 - Graduation: 9

The study that combines aspects from the fields of industrial design, computer science and electrical engineering with current technology. Students develop a view of creativity and a keen eye for interaction and potential of new technologies. During the study I followed an elective in New Media (3D-modeling and game design). For my graduation project I worked on the design of an educational escape room for a local history museum in Twente showing understanding in game-based mechanics, educational value and AR-development.

#### University of Trento Minor Italy Human Computer Interaction

For my minor I followed part of the Master Human Computer Interaction with courses such as social interaction, e-learning, affective computing and mind-brain interaction focusing more on the psychological and social effects of incorporating new technologies into people's lives.

## Regius College Schagen

#### Pre-university education (VWO)

- EM/CM profile
- Final Paper about the influence and usage of crowdfunding for business.
- Participated in a project for high School Students called "Spannend Ondernemen" that focusses on innovative business concepts in which our group project won the first prize out of 50+ groups.

ep 2016- Feb 2017

16-2019

Sep 2018 - Feb 2019

2010-2016

#### Work Experience

#### Extra Skills

- Touch Typing
- First Aid (EHBO) Certificate

#### Green Team Twente Graphic Designer and Public Relations

A fullfilled this part-time position in the sustainably oriented student team called Green Team Twente. For the team I handled the visual designs, social media and branding campaigns in a small team.

- Designing promotional merchandise and strategies to promote our hydrogen eco-car and race. The team worked together to put sustainablity on company agendas.
- Winner of the Communication Award in the SEM (2020)

# University of Twente Education Evaluation of Creative Technology Part of a small comittee of students that held evaluations to ensuring the quality of education of the study programme Creative Technology.

- Organising short lunch-discussion and taking care of the promotion and contacting participants.
- Acting as the conversation leader in group conversations and discussions to ensure all opinions are valued and heard.

#### Tetem: Art & Technology Allround Gallery Assistant

Informing visitors and guiding them through the art and technology exhibitions by giving fitting information to a visitors about the exhibited pieces.

- Responsible for promotion targeted at University Students through activities and social media.
- Assistant teacher for children and groups during workshops about new technologies such as 3D-pens, video editing and programming Ozobots.

#### University of Twente Promotional Events (multiple positions)

- Part of a team that guides and hosts 150+ students and parents during the open days to promote the University of Twente and specifically the study Creative Technology – through answering questions, showing demos and holding brainstorming session.
- Visiting high schools to represent the university through holding public presentations and answering questions during information markets.

Vomar Voordeelmarkt Cashier with administrative responsibilities (Mar 2015 - Aug 2016)

#### Volunteering & Activism

#### Kick-In - Photographer / Media Team

Volunteering position as part of the photography crew at the University of Twente introduction period (event with over 5000 participants).

• Taking pictures, editing and uploading over 1000 photos in a short period of 9 days. The events range from corporate to sports to social and the photos convey a feeling of enthusiasm and happiness to the viewers.

## S.A proto – Multiple Committees (including Graphical Design, Photography and Event organisation)

Throughout my studies I have been an active voluntary member of committees. An example is the symposium committee, organizing the 'from pixel to purchase' symposium with companies such as Audi, Twinkls Augmented Reality and Datatrics. For the symposium event I designed a corporate identity, organised promotional activities and contacted and organized finding speakers.

016- Current

2018

2016- Current

rent

2016 - Current